# TEO, BRENDAN WEI ZHI

**C**: + 6016 - 383 6202

(a): brendan\_twz@hotmail.com (b): linkedin.com/in/brendantwz (c): github.com/Brendantwz

: brendantwz.com

## **About Me**

Efficiency-driven, analytical, and coachable Engineer with up to 4-years of professional experience looking to grow with your company. Seeking a career shift in areas of development roles to take advantages of my skills in script writing, test debug, validation, and verification. Nevertheless, an avid practitioner of growth-mindset and in life-long learning. Currently, upskilling on Full-stack Web development course with several of personal projects to-date.

#### **Work Experience**

### Freelance - Penang, Malaysia

Front-end Web Developer

( Nov 2023 - Current )

- **Delivered a single-page responsive website** that display overview services for a Mixed-martial arts gym in Penang called Wasp MMA Gym within 1-month.
- Provide monthly web maintenance service of **ensuring website** is **running without any potential downtime** with monthly report of website health.

#### Intel Corporation - Penang, Malaysia

SoC Design Engineer

(Apr 2022 - Jun 2023)

- **Developed and deployed a window script** to improve debugger's debugging task, optimized users' effectiveness to churn out summary failing log by 44%.
- **Analyzed and resolved 59 unique bug** reports submitted by debuggers within a 3-month timeframe.
- Addressed and **resolved 19 design and simulator bugs** within a 3-weeks' timeframe while working closely with technical lead and principal engineer.
- Collaborated 2 cross team to maintained project delivery timeline. By supporting on post-silicon debugging challenges with respective stakeholder.

Soft-IP Validation Engineer

(Mar 2021 – Apr 2022)

- Collaborated cross team support on coverage test validation and writing with improvement from 27% to 98% coverage hit within 2-weeks ahead of project deadline.
- Developed and deployed email bug reporting system written in Shell with CRON tool. Improve work efficiency by 15% after deployment.
- **Developed and implemented a bucketization script** that is used to sort 10000+ test failures based on signature on weekly test regression.
- **Spearheaded** a **test migration effort** of legacy to upcoming project within 2-weeks with 70+ features to match the project requirement.

**Graduate Technical Trainee** 

( Nov 2019 - Mar 2021 )

- Delivered Test coverage writing and testing on 1 feature with improvement from 51% to 87% coverage hit ahead of schedule projection by 1 week.
- Supported a feature owner by shadowing as an execution owner to validate RTL designs and test debug.
- Delivered 1st level bug/error with data log to revise with feature owner. Solved 27 high-level errors independently.

#### **Projects**

**brendantwz.com** – Personal portfolio website

( Dec 2023 - present )

- Developed using the technology stack of **Bootstrap templating with HTML/CSS**. Publicly stored in Github
- Create digital presence by exposing my personal capabilities with projects that I personally worked

**SimplyPress** – Blog post app for mock-up article planning

( Nov 2023 - 4 weeks )

- Developed using the technology stack of Embedded Javascript (EJS), CSS, Javascript, Express.js, Node.js and Bootstrap. Publicly stored in Github
- Available features are adding, remove, edit post. Post consisted of Author Name, Title of Blog Post, Content, and Genre.

waspmmagym.com - Paid Project by a Mixed Martial Arts Gym to create an infographic responsive website to display their services

( Dec 2023 – 5 weeks)

- Developed using the technology stack solely frontend Bootstrap templating with HTML/CSS, Javascript, FontAwesome
- Single-page landing page segmented to 7 section Classes, Testimonial, About, Team, FAQ, Merch, Contact
- Hosted the website via Web hosting service and setup on-page SEO and Google search indexing with sitemaps

QRFreg - URL to QR code generator replica

( Dec 2023 – 3 weeks )

- Developed using the technology stack of Bulma with HTML/CSS, Vanilla Javascript, Node.js and Ionicons. Publicly stored and hosted in Github.
- Responsive single page URL to QR code functionality prevents non-url to be converted and to display QR code if URL is valid.

# **Education**

# Northumbria University Newcastle

Bachelor in Electrical and Electronic Engineering ( 1st CLASS HONOURS )

Graduation Date: Oct 2019

Graduation Date: Nov 2017

Organizations/Awards: Silver Medalist Innovative Project, Student Advisor for Engineering Society and Organizing Team

# **KDU Penang University College**

Diploma in Electrical and Electronic Engineering (Microelectronics) (CGPA: 3.74)

Organizations/Awards: Dean's Honor List, Peer-Assisted Study Session tutor, 1st Runner Up IHL-Malaysia Start-up Challenge 2016/17

**Technical:** 

HTML (Intermediate), CSS (Intermediate), Python (Basic), JavaScript (Intermediate), jQuery (Intermediate), Git (Intermediate), On-page SEO (Basic) Node.js (Intermediate), Express.js (Intermediate), Debugging (Proficient), Batch/UNIX Shell (Proficient), Bootstrap (Proficient), Bulma.io (Basic)

Interpersonal: Communication (Advance), Analytical (Proficient), Coachable (Proficient), Collaborative (Proficient), Time Management (Intermediate), Detail-oriented (Intermediate), Creative Problem-Solving (Intermediate), Adaptable (Intermediate)

**Certifications** 

Career Essentials in Generative AI - Microsoft and LinkedIn Online Course

Issued on July 2023

The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp – Udemy Online Course (In progress)

Expectancy Completion: Feb 2024

English (Native), Mandarin (Conversational), Malay (Conversational), Hokkien (Native) Languages

Co-Founder of Wasp MMA Gym – Ms Claire Li Ji

SoC Design Engineer - Mr Nam Khoon, Teh

E: nam.khoon.teh@intel.com E: <u>wasp.mmagym@gmail.com</u> M: +60-12-728-7232 M: +60-12-728-7232

References